

# THANISH AHAMED

BSc (Hons) in Information Technology Specializing in Software Engineering (Reading)

thanishahamed321@gmail.com | +94776271771 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/thanish-ahamed555/

## **PROFILE**

Computer Science Student who is highly skilled and knowledgeable in coding and takes a great interest in solving problems using logical knowledge. Has a strong appetite to learn new things and is a team player who is willing to contribute to the success of the team even under pressure. A quick learner who has great expertise in SQL, Java and MERN technology.

### JOB SPECIFIC SKILLS

- Developed excellent **communication skills** by facilitating professional presentations, working with different teams, and solving minor disputes within my own capacity by taking the lead within the team.
- Gained sound knowledge in **Java by using object-oriented concepts and design patterns** to work on the backend of the web application that was developed for the completion of the semester module.
- Well-versed with SQL by developing web applications that utilized SQL server management studio and My SQL workbench.
- Well-versed with **ReactJs**, **NodeJs**, and **Mongo DB** by completing online certifications/ courses.
- Familiar with JavaScript through using the language for front-end and back-end validations.
- Comfortable with **Python** by completing an online course in Free code camp.
- Hands-on experience working with WordPress.
- Proficient in **Django** framework by developing few applications by self-learning.
- Well-versed with Kotlin by developing mobile apps.
- Learned about Data Structures & Algorithms and able to analyze algorithms.

## **EDUCATION**

2021 - Present	-Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology BSc (Hons) in Information Technology specialized in Software Engineering – <b>Current GPA – 3.73</b>
2018 - 2020	-Kingswood College Kandy - Advanced Level — Physical Science 2B C Chemistry — B   Physics — B   Mathematics — C
2012 – 2017	-Ranabima royal College Kandy - Ordinary Level — 9A's
2017 - 2011	-Gampola Zahira College

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

- Junior Web Developer Worked as a Junior web developer at FlaminQo solutions from 16<sup>th</sup> of January 2023 to 16<sup>th</sup> of April 2023.
- Online Maths tutor Worked as an online maths tutor at Third Space Global from 1<sup>st</sup> of November 2022 to 31<sup>st</sup> of March 2023.

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Scientific Computing with Python Free Code Camp
- Java (Basic) Hacker Rank
- **SQL** (Basic, Intermediate) Hacker Rank
- Front End development Libraries (React, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, Redux) – Free Code Camp
- Problem Solving (Basic) Hacker Rank
- React (Basic) Hacker Rank
- JavaScript (Basic) Hacker Rank
- CSS (Basic) -Hacker Rank
- Back End development and APIs Free Code Camp

## CERTIFICATIONS

- International Mathematics Olympiad training program 2012 1 st place Central Province
- National Mathematics Olympiad competition 2014,2016
- All island School inventor's competition (Invention) -2016 [Merit]
- Understanding the world through science 2013 Institute of fundamental studies Sri Lanka 1 st place
- 9th International abacus and mental arithmetic competition 2009. Chennai, India 3rd runner up
- SAHASAK NIMAVUM 2017 National Exhibition for Inventions & Innovation -participation
- 4th National SIP Abacus and Mental arithmetic competition 2008 -champion
- Dean's List Certificate 1<sup>st</sup> year 1<sup>st</sup> semester, 1<sup>st</sup> year 2<sup>nd</sup> semester

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Online Help Desk

A Help Desk system was created as a project with a team of 3 individuals. Worked on this project by taking the lead. Languages such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript were utilized to build the front end of the helpdesk while Java was utilized to build the back end of the system. The database was entirely managed using SQL where MySQL workbench was utilized to configure it. Object-oriented concepts and design patterns were used throughout.

## Public Transport Reservation System

A bus reservation system was created from scratch using languages such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for the front end and PHP for the back end. The database for this system was entirely managed in Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio using SQL. Worked as the lead and completed the entire project within a short span of time by sticking to the deadline.

## Dental Clinic Management System

A web application for a dental clinic was created from scratch for the 2<sup>nd</sup> year 2<sup>nd</sup> semester module. This application was created using MERN stack technology. This was a group project. I contributed to the project by developing the doctor management functionality completely. Got good experience on React Js, Node Js while developing the application.

# Job Portal – Mobile App

A mobile app was created for the semester module assignment. This was a mobile app that supports companies to upload jobs in their organization and the common users can apply for these jobs. And at the same time users can post their freelance work. This app was created from scratch using Kotlin. For the database we used SQLite. I was the leader for this group project and led the team successfully and finished the project within the given deadline.

### **SKILLS**

- **Technical Skills:** HTML | CSS | C | C++ | JavaScript | Java | SQL | PHP | React | Python | Kotlin | Problem-Solving Certificate | Problem-Solving badges | object-oriented programming | Design Patterns | Front End Development Libraries
- Languages: English, Tamil, Sinhala
- Personal Skills: Communication, Leadership, Time Management, Creativity, Attention to Detail, Self-Development

#### REFERENCES

#### Zamreen Zarook

Corporate Trainer/Business/Consultant/Lecturer Director – Glinmax Holdings (Pvt)Ltd., Tolmark Training & Consulting(Pvt)Ltd.

Phone: +94777854965

Email: zamreenzi@gmail.com

# Safwan Mohamed

Computer Science and Engineering (University of Moratuwa)

Profession: Digital Banking- Assistant manager,

Arab Bank

Phone: +971506079536

Email: safwanmoha@gmail.com